[
    {
        "question": "1. What additional information is contained in the 12-bit extended system ID of a BPDU?",
        "choices": ["MAC address", "VLAN ID", "IP address", "port ID"],
        "answer": "VLAN ID"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. During the implementation of Spanning Tree Protocol, all switches are rebooted by the network administrator. What is the first step of the spanning-tree election process?",
        "choices": ["Each switch with a lower root ID than its neighbor will not send BPDUs.", "All the switches send out BPDUs advertising themselves as the root bridge.", "Each switch determines the best path to forward traffic.", "Each switch determines what port to block to prevent a loop from occurring."],
        "answer": "All the switches send out BPDUs advertising themselves as the root bridge."
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Which STP port role is adopted by a switch port if there is no other port with a lower cost to the root bridge?",
        "choices": ["designated port", "root port", "alternate", "disabled port"],
        "answer": "root port"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. If no bridge priority is configured in PVST, which criteria is considered when electing the root bridge?",
        "choices": ["lowest MAC address", "lowest IP address", "highest IP address", "highest MAC address"],
        "answer": "lowest MAC address"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What is the function of STP in a scalable network?",
        "choices": ["It decreases the size of the failure domain to contain the impact of failures.", "It protects the edge of the enterprise network from malicious activity.", "It combines multiple switch trunk links to act as one logical link for increased bandwidth.", "It disables redundant paths to eliminate Layer 2 loops."],
        "answer": "It disables redundant paths to eliminate Layer 2 loops."
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What is a characteristic of spanning tree?",
        "choices": ["It is enabled by default on Cisco switches.", "It is used to discover information about an adjacent Cisco device.", "It has a TTL mechanism that works at Layer 2.", "It prevents propagation of Layer 2 broadcast frames."],
        "answer": "It is enabled by default on Cisco switches."
    },
    {
        "question": "13. Which spanning tree standard supports only one root bridge so that traffic from all VLANs flows over the same path?",
        "choices": ["PVST+", "802.1D", "MST", "Rapid PVST"],
        "answer": "802.1D"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What is the purpose of the Spanning Tree Protocol (STP)?",
        "choices": ["creates smaller collision domains", "prevents routing loops on a router", "prevents Layer 2 loops", "allows Cisco devices to exchange routing table updates", "creates smaller broadcast domains"],
        "answer": "prevents Layer 2 loops"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. What is the value used to determine which port on a non-root bridge will become a root port in a STP network?",
        "choices": ["the path cost", "the highest MAC address of all the ports in the switch", "the lowest MAC address of all the ports in the switch", "the VTP revision number"],
        "answer": "the path cost"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. Refer to the exhibit. Which switch will be the root bridge after the election process is complete?",
        "choices": ["S1", "S2", "S3", "S4"],
        "answer": "S2"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. A small company network has six interconnected Layer 2 switches. Currently all switches are using the default bridge priority value. Which value can be used to configure the bridge priority of one of the switches to ensure that it becomes the root bridge in this design?",
        "choices": ["1", "28672", "32768", "34816", "61440"],
        "answer": "28672"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. Refer to the exhibit. The administrator tried to create an EtherChannel between S1 and the other two switches via the commands that are shown, but was unsuccessful. What is the problem?",
        "choices": ["Traffic cannot be sent to two different switches through the same EtherChannel link.", "Traffic cannot be sent to two different switches, but only to two different devices like an EtherChannel-enabled server and a switch.", "Traffic can only be sent to two different switches if EtherChannel is implemented on Gigabit Ethernet interfaces.", "Traffic can only be sent to two different switches if EtherChannel is implemented on Layer 3 switches."],
        "answer": "Traffic cannot be sent to two different switches through the same EtherChannel link."
    },
    {
        "question": "20. Which statement is true regarding the use of PAgP to create EtherChannels?",
        "choices": ["It requires full duplex.", "It increases the number of ports that are participating in spanning tree.", "It requires more physical links than LACP does.", "It mandates that an even number of ports (2, 4, 6, etc.) be used for aggregation.", "It is Cisco proprietary."],
        "answer": "It is Cisco proprietary."
    },
    {
        "question": "22. Refer to the exhibit. On the basis of the output that is shown, what can be determined about the EtherChannel bundle?",
        "choices": ["The EtherChannel bundle is down.", "Two Gigabit Ethernet ports are used to form the EtherChannel.", "A Cisco proprietary protocol was used to negotiate the EtherChannel link.", "The EtherChannel bundle is operating at both Layer 2 and Layer 3."],
        "answer": "A Cisco proprietary protocol was used to negotiate the EtherChannel link."
    },
    {
        "question": "24. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring an EtherChannel link between two switches, SW1 and SW2. Which statement describes the effect after the commands are issued on SW1 and SW2?",
        "choices": ["The EtherChannel is established after SW2 initiates the link request.", "The EtherChannel is established after SW1 initiates the link request.", "The EtherChannel is established without negotiation.", "The EtherChannel fails to establish."],
        "answer": "The EtherChannel fails to establish."
    },
    {
        "question": "25. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring an EtherChannel link between two switches, SW1 and SW2. However, the EtherChannel link fails to establish. What change in configuration would correct the problem?",
        "choices": ["Configure SW2 EtherChannel mode to desirable.", "Configure SW2 EtherChannel mode to on.", "Configure SW1 EtherChannel mode to on.", "Configure SW2 EtherChannel mode to auto."],
        "answer": "Configure SW2 EtherChannel mode to desirable."
    },
    {
        "question": "26. A network administrator configured an EtherChannel link with three interfaces between two switches. What is the result if one of the three interfaces is down?",
        "choices": ["The remaining two interfaces continue to load balance traffic.", "The remaining two interfaces become separate links between the two switches.", "One interface becomes an active link for data traffic and the other becomes a backup link.", "The EtherChannel fails."],
        "answer": "The remaining two interfaces continue to load balance traffic."
    },
    {
        "question": "27. A network administrator is configuring an EtherChannel link between switches SW1 and SW2 by using the command SW1(config-if-range)# channel-group 1 mode auto. Which command must be used on SW2 to enable this EtherChannel?",
        "choices": ["SW2(config-if-range)# channel-group 1 mode passive", "SW2(config-if-range)# channel-group 1 mode desirable", "SW2(config-if-range)# channel-group 1 mode on", "SW2(config-if-range)# channel-group 1 mode active"],
        "answer": "SW2(config-if-range)# channel-group 1 mode desirable"
    },
    {
        "question": "28. Which technology is an open protocol standard that allows switches to automatically bundle physical ports into a single logical link?",
        "choices": ["PAgP", "LACP", "Multilink PPP", "DTP"],
        "answer": "LACP"
    },
    {
        "question": "29. What is a requirement to configure a trunking EtherChannel between two switches?",
        "choices": ["The allowed range of VLANs must be the same on both switches.", "The participating interfaces must be assigned the same VLAN number on both switches.", "The participating interfaces must be physically contiguous on a switch.", "The participating interfaces must be on the same module on a switch."],
        "answer": "The allowed range of VLANs must be the same on both switches."
    },
    {
        "question": "31. A switch is configured to run STP. What term describes a non-root port that is permitted to forward traffic on the network?",
        "choices": ["root port", "designated port", "alternate port", "disabled"],
        "answer": "designated port"
    },
    {
        "question": "33. Refer to the exhibit. What are the possible port roles for ports A, B, C, and D in this RSTP-enabled network?",
        "choices": ["alternate, designated, root, root", "designated, alternate, root, root", "alternate, root, designated, root", "designated, root, alternate, root"],
        "answer": "alternate, designated, root, root"
    },
    {
        "question": "34. Refer to the exhibit. Which switching technology would allow each access layer switch link to be aggregated to provide more bandwidth between each Layer 2 switch and the Layer 3 switch?",
        "choices": ["trunking", "HSRP", "PortFast", "EtherChannel"],
        "answer": "EtherChannel"
    },
    {
        "question": "35. Refer to the exhibit. An administrator wants to form an EtherChannel between the two switches by using the Port Aggregation Protocol. If switch S1 is configured to be in auto mode, which mode should be configured on S2 to form the EtherChannel?",
        "choices": ["auto", "on", "off", "desirable"],
        "answer": "desirable"
    },
    {
        "question": "36. Which set of configuration commands issued on SW1 will successfully complete the EtherChannel link between SW1 and SW2?",
        "choices": [
            "interface GigabitEthernet0/1\nno shutdown",
            "interface Port-channel 1\nno shutdown",
            "interface GigabitEthernet0/2\nchannel-group 2 mode desirable",
            "interface GigabitEthernet0/1\nchannel-group 1 mode desirable"
        ],
        "answer": "interface GigabitEthernet0/1\nchannel-group 1 mode desirable"
    },
    {
        "question": "37. A set of switches is being connected in a LAN topology. Which STP bridge priority value will make it least likely for the switch to be selected as the root?",
        "choices": ["65535", "4096", "32768", "61440"],
        "answer": "61440"
    },
    {
        "question": "39. Which port role is assigned to the switch port that has the lowest cost to reach the root bridge?",
        "choices": ["designated port", "disabled port", "root port", "non-designated port"],
        "answer": "root port"
    },
    {
        "question": "40. A switch is configured to run STP. What term describes the switch port closest, in terms of overall cost, to the root bridge?",
        "choices": ["root port", "designated port", "alternate port", "disabled"],
        "answer": "root port"
    },
    {
        "question": "42. A switch is configured to run STP. What term describes a field used to specify a VLAN ID?",
        "choices": ["extended system ID", "port ID", "bridge priority", "bridge ID"],
        "answer": "extended system ID"
    },
    {
        "question": "43. A switch is configured to run STP. What term describes the reference point for all path calculations?",
        "choices": ["root bridge", "root port", "designated port", "alternate port"],
        "answer": "root bridge"
    },
    {
        "question": "44. A switch is configured to run STP. What term describes a field that has a default value of 32,768 and is the initial deciding factor when electing a root bridge?",
        "choices": ["bridge priority", "MAC Address", "extended system ID", "bridge ID"],
        "answer": "bridge priority"
    },
    {
        "question": "45. Which statement describes an EtherChannel implementation?",
        "choices": ["EtherChannel operates only at Layer 2.", "PAgP cannot be used in conjunction with EtherChannel.", "A trunked port can be part of an EtherChannel bundle.", "EtherChannel can support up to a maximum of ten separate links."],
        "answer": "A trunked port can be part of an EtherChannel bundle."
    },
    {
        "question": "46. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator issued the show etherchannel summary command on the switch S1. What conclusion can be drawn?",
        "choices": ["The EtherChannel is suspended.", "The EtherChannel is not functional.", "The port aggregation protocol PAgP is misconfigured.", "FastEthernet ports Fa0/1, Fa0/2, and Fa0/3 do not join the EtherChannel."],
        "answer": "The EtherChannel is not functional."
    },
    {
        "question": "47. Which statement describes a characteristic of EtherChannel?",
        "choices": ["It can combine up to a maximum of 4 physical links.", "It can bundle mixed types of 100 Mb/s and 1Gb/s Ethernet links.", "It consists of multiple parallel links between a switch and a router.", "It is made by combining multiple physical links that are seen as one link between two switches."],
        "answer": "It is made by combining multiple physical links that are seen as one link between two switches."
    },
    {
        "question": "50. Refer to the exhibit. An EtherChannel was configured between switches S1 and S2, but the interfaces do not form an EtherChannel. What is the problem?",
        "choices": ["The interface port-channel number has to be different on each switch.", "The switch ports were not configured with speed and duplex mode.", "The switch ports have to be configured as access ports with each port having a VLAN assigned.", "The EtherChannel was not configured with the same allowed range of VLANs on each interface."],
        "answer": "The EtherChannel was not configured with the same allowed range of VLANs on each interface."
    },
    {
        "question": "51. When EtherChannel is configured, which mode will force an interface into a port channel without exchanging aggregation protocol packets?",
        "choices": ["active", "auto", "on", "desirable"],
        "answer": "on"
    },
    {
        "question": "53. Which protocol provides up to 16 instances of RSTP, combines many VLANs with the same physical and logical topology into a common RSTP instance, and provides support for PortFast, BPDU guard, BPDU filter, root guard, and loop guard?",
        "choices": ["STP", "Rapid PVST+", "PVST+", "MST"],
        "answer": "MST"
    },
    {
        "question": "54. What is the outcome of a Layer 2 broadcast storm?",
        "choices": ["Routers will take over the forwarding of frames as switches become congested.", "New traffic is discarded by the switch because it is unable to be processed.", "CSMA/CD will cause each host to continue transmitting frames.", "ARP broadcast requests are returned to the transmitting host."],
        "answer": "New traffic is discarded by the switch because it is unable to be processed."
    },
    {
        "question": "56. A network administrator has configured an EtherChannel between two switches that are connected via four trunk links. If the physical interface for one of the trunk links changes to a down state, what happens to the EtherChannel?",
        "choices": ["Spanning Tree Protocol will transition the failed physical interface into forwarding mode.", "Spanning Tree Protocol will recalculate the remaining trunk links.", "The EtherChannel will transition to a down state.", "The EtherChannel will remain functional."],
        "answer": "The EtherChannel will remain functional."
    }
]